Welcome back English learners.
欢迎回来，英语学习者。
My name is Marco and I'm joined here by the lovely...
我是 Marco，今天和我一起的是可爱的……
Erika.
Erika。
And today we're going to be bringing you another great lesson, one of the lessons that you
今天我们为大家带来另一堂精彩的课程，这是你们
requested.
要求的一课。
Yes, that's right.
是的，没错。
Actually, Maxim, Maxim S requested this one.
实际上，是 Maxim，Maxim S 要求了这一课。
Right.
对。
I think he's really into research and investigation.
我觉得他对研究和调查非常感兴趣。
So we're bringing you a great lesson about this topic.
所以我们为大家带来了一堂关于这个主题的精彩课程。
Okay.
好的。
So I'm really excited to hear this dialogue all about research.
我很兴奋能听到这段关于研究的对话。
So why don't we start listening to two university professors discussing an important question.
那我们开始听两位大学教授讨论一个重要问题吧。
We've been over this a thousand times.
我们已经讨论过这个问题一千遍了。
The data is irrefutable.
数据是无可辩驳的。
Look, we've done extensive research, built studies and read the literature, and there
听着，我们做了广泛的研究，建立了研究项目，阅读了文献，而且有
is conclusive evidence to support my theory.
确凿的证据支持我的理论。
Horowitz, I beg to differ.
Horowitz，我不同意。
Even in your most recent study, the investigative approach was flawed.
即使在你最近的研究中，调查方法也有缺陷。
You know as well as I do, the collection of data was not systematic and there's a large
你和我一样清楚，数据收集并不系统，而且存在很大的
margin of error.
误差范围。
To draw a definitive conclusion based on that data would be misleading.
基于这些数据得出一个确定的结论会误导人。
That is preposterous.
这太荒谬了。
You are trying to single handedly solve one of the world's greatest mysteries and yet
你试图独自解决世界上最大的谜团之一，然而
you're oblivious to the fact that you're wrong.
你却对自己错了这个事实浑然不觉。
I am not wrong.
我没有错。
The chicken came first.
鸡先出现。
No, the egg came first.
不，蛋先出现。
The chicken.
鸡。
Egg.
蛋。
The egg.
The chicken.
鸡。
The egg.
蛋。
All right, so interesting.
好了，真有趣。
Which came first, the chicken or the egg?
哪个先出现，鸡还是蛋？
It's an age old question, isn't it?
这是一个古老的问题，对吧？
And apparently they are not going to agree anytime soon.
显然他们短期内不会达成一致。
All right, well, what they can agree about is this awesome language.
好吧，他们能达成一致的是这些很棒的语言。
So why don't we take a look at it now in Language Takeaway.
那我们来看看“语言要点”部分吧。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Okay on Language Takeaway today we have some really great words and this first one is really
好的，今天的“语言要点”里有一些非常棒的词，第一个
good.
特别好。
Irrefutable.
无可辩驳的。
The data is irrefutable.
数据是无可辩驳的。
Okay so if the professor says that the data is irrefutable, what does he mean by that?
好的，如果教授说数据是无可辩驳的，他是什么意思？
He's saying that you cannot deny it.
他是说你无法否认它。
It is really, really true.
它非常非常真实。
It is really true.
它非常真实。
There is no way this is a lie.
这绝不可能是谎言。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
Irrefutable evidence for example.
比如，无可辩驳的证据。
Yeah, that's a great phrase.
是的，那是个很棒的短语。
All right, so the professor complained that Dr. Horowitz's experiment was flawed.
好的，教授抱怨说 Horowitz 博士的实验有缺陷。
Flawed.
有缺陷的。
So flawed, is that an adjective, a verb or a noun?
那么“有缺陷的”是形容词、动词还是名词？
It is an adjective here.
这里它是形容词。
Now when something is flawed, there is a problem with it, right?
当某物有缺陷时，它有问题，对吧？
There's a mistake.
有错误。
Okay, so it has an error.
好的，所以它有错误。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So the professor is saying that his experiment has a flaw.
所以教授说他的实验有缺陷。
A mistake, exactly.
一个错误，没错。
So flawed is the adjective of a flaw.
所以“有缺陷的”是“缺陷”的形容词形式。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
Now the reason that his study or his experiment was flawed is because it was not systematic.
他的研究或实验有缺陷的原因是因为它不系统。
Systematic.
系统的。
So systematic, that's an interesting word.
所以“系统的”，这是个有趣的词。
Now I think we can recognize the word system in here, right?
我想我们能认出里面的“系统”这个词，对吧？
Right.
对。
So when something is systematic, it follows a process.
所以当某物是系统的，它遵循一个过程。
A certain order.
一定的顺序。
Yes, a certain system.
是的，一定的系统。
Right.
对。
So that's basically what systematic means, to follow a certain order, to be more organized,
所以这就是“系统的”的基本意思，遵循一定的顺序，更有组织性，
right?
对吧？
Exactly, yeah.
没错，是的。
Okay.
好的。
And what about our next word?
那我们的下一个词呢？
Preposterous.
荒谬的。
That is preposterous.
这太荒谬了。
I love this phrase.
我喜欢这个短语。
It usually goes together, right?
它通常一起出现，对吧？
That is preposterous.
这太荒谬了。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay, so what does it mean when I say that?
好的，那我说这个是什么意思？
It means it's absurd.
意思是它很荒唐。
It's ridiculous.
它很可笑。
Right.
对。
It doesn't make sense.
它说不通。
I can't believe you said that.
我不敢相信你说了这个。
All right.
好的。
Well, this is a really interesting phrase, but I think it's a little bit more common
嗯，这是个非常有趣的短语，但我觉得它更常见于
when it's used by older people.
年长的人使用。
Yeah.
是的。
I don't think, I don't really see a young person going up to someone and say, hey, that's
我不觉得，我不太会看到年轻人走到别人面前说，嘿，那太
preposterous.
荒谬了。
Yeah, but it is a wonderful phrase.
是的，但它是个很棒的短语。
Now our final phrase for takeaway, oblivious.
现在我们“语言要点”的最后一个短语是“浑然不觉的”。
Oblivious.
浑然不觉的。
You're oblivious to the facts.
你对事实浑然不觉。
So a person that is oblivious to something.
所以一个对某事浑然不觉的人。
They don't know or they're unaware.
他们不知道或没意识到。
Okay, so they ignore maybe the facts or they don't see it.
好的，所以他们可能忽略了事实或没看到它。
Yeah.
是的。
You're oblivious to the fact that we're in a recession.
你对我们在经济衰退中这个事实浑然不觉。
Okay, or he is completely oblivious.
好的，或者他完全浑然不觉。
You can just say it like that, right?
你可以直接这么说，对吧？
Yeah, he doesn't know.
是的，他不知道。
Okay, so we took a look at some of the great vocabulary we found in the dialogue, but there
好的，我们看了一些在对话中找到的很好的词汇，但
were also some really good phrases that I think we should look at.
还有一些非常好的短语，我觉得我们应该看看。
Okay, and let's take a look at those in Putting It Together.
好的，让我们在“融会贯通”部分看看这些。
Putting It Together.
融会贯通。
You know, Marco, one of the things I love about English is the way that words seem to
你知道，Marco，我喜欢英语的一点是词语似乎能
fit together, like blocks coming together.
很好地搭配在一起，就像积木拼在一起。
And here we have a lot of great examples of these words that fit together really nicely.
这里我们有很多很好的例子，这些词搭配得非常好。
Okay, so why don't we look at those?
好的，那我们来看看这些吧？
And our first one now is extensive research.
我们的第一个是“广泛的研究”。
Extensive research.
广泛的研究。
All right, so we know extensive means?
好的，我们知道“广泛的”意思是？
A lot.
很多。
Yeah.
是的。
So that's really good when you put it together, extensive research.
所以当你把它们放在一起，“广泛的研究”很好。
It means you have?
意思是你有？
A lot of research.
很多研究。
You have really studied, you have really looked things up.
你确实研究过，确实查过资料。
Okay, extensive research.
好的，广泛的研究。
Another great research-related phrase here is conclusive evidence.
另一个与研究相关的很棒短语是“确凿的证据”。
Conclusive evidence.
确凿的证据。
All right, now, the first word there, conclusive.
好的，第一个词，“确凿的”。
When something is conclusive, you can't argue with it.
当某物是确凿的，你无法反驳它。
It's the final decision.
这是最终的决定。
All right, well, the professor complained that Horowitz's investigative approach was
好的，教授抱怨说 Horowitz 的调查方法有缺陷，
flawed, right?
对吧？
So this is our next phrase, investigative approach.
所以这是我们的下一个短语，“调查方法”。
Investigative approach.
调查方法。
Okay, so I remember the word investigate is a verb.
好的，我记得“调查”是动词。
Yes.
是的。
But in this case, it's a?
但在这个情况下，它是？
It's an adjective.
它是形容词。
So when something is investigative, it's obviously having to do with?
所以当某物是调查性的，它显然与什么有关？
An investigation.
调查。
So the approach or the...
所以方法或……
So when he said investigative approach.
所以当他说调查方法时。
Just the...
就是……
I mean, just simply the way you investigate the problem.
我的意思是，就是你调查问题的方式。
The way he investigated.
他调查的方式。
Okay, very interesting.
好的，非常有趣。
What about this other phrase that I saw?
那我看到的另一个短语呢？
It was really interesting.
它非常有趣。
Definitive conclusion.
确定的结论。
So a definitive conclusion.
所以一个确定的结论。
All right, well, again, I think we know the word conclusion, right?
好的，再次，我想我们知道“结论”这个词，对吧？
Okay.
好的。
So it's a final judgment or decision.
所以它是一个最终的判断或决定。
All right.
好的。
When something is definitive, you can't argue with it or change it.
当某物是确定的，你无法反驳或改变它。
Okay, so the conclusion or the final result is final, like there is no way of arguing
好的，所以结论或最终结果是最终的，就像无法
it.
反驳它。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
All right.
Well, that's great language.
嗯，那是很棒的语言。
So why don't we listen to it one more time in the dialogue?
那我们再听一遍对话吧？
We've been over this a thousand times.
我们已经讨论过这个问题一千遍了。
The data is irrefutable.
数据是无可辩驳的。
Look, we've done extensive research, built studies and read the literature, and there
听着，我们做了广泛的研究，建立了研究项目，阅读了文献，而且有
is conclusive evidence to support my theory.
确凿的证据支持我的理论。
Horowitz, I beg to differ.
Horowitz，我不同意。
Even in your most recent study, the investigative approach was flawed.
即使在你最近的研究中，调查方法也有缺陷。
You know as well as I do, the collection of data was not systematic and there's a large
你和我一样清楚，数据收集并不系统，而且存在很大的
margin of error.
误差范围。
To draw a definitive conclusion based on that data would be misleading.
基于这些数据得出一个确定的结论会误导人。
That is preposterous.
这太荒谬了。
You are trying to single-handedly solve one of the world's greatest mysteries, and yet
你试图独自解决世界上最大的谜团之一，然而
you're oblivious to the fact that you're wrong.
你却对自己错了这个事实浑然不觉。
I am not wrong.
我没有错。
The chicken came first.
鸡先出现。
No, the egg came first.
不，蛋先出现。
The chicken.
鸡。
Egg.
蛋。
The chicken.
鸡。
The egg.
蛋。
The chicken.
鸡。
The egg.
蛋。
The chicken.
鸡。
The egg.
蛋。
So, an interesting question.
所以，一个有趣的问题。
What do you think?
你怎么看？
What came first, the chicken or the egg?
是先有鸡还是先有蛋？
Well, you ask me, it was the egg.
嗯，要我说，是先有蛋。
It was the egg?
是先有蛋？
Yeah.
是啊。
Interesting.
有意思。
What about why did the chicken cross the road?
那为什么鸡要过马路呢？
To get to the other side.
为了到对面去。
Do you think that's really the reason?
你觉得这真的是原因吗？
Well, there's a million different reasons, but this is great.
嗯，有无数种原因，但这挺棒的。
I'm glad you brought that up because this is like the classic English joke.
很高兴你提到这个，因为这就像经典的英语笑话。
The classic English joke, right?
经典的英语笑话，对吧？
Why did the chicken cross the road?
为什么鸡要过马路？
And the answer is always...
答案总是……
Well, there are a million answers.
嗯，有无数种答案。
So do you guys know any chicken jokes?
你们知道什么关于鸡的笑话吗？
Yeah.
知道。
Why don't you come to our website, EnglishPod.com, and on the comment section, why don't you
不如来我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，在评论区
leave us your thoughts on what came first, the chicken or the egg, and why do you think
留下你对先有鸡还是先有蛋的看法，以及你认为
the chicken crossed the road?
鸡为什么要过马路？
All right.
好的。
Well, we really look forward to hearing your ideas, and Marco and I will be around to answer
嗯，我们真的很期待听到你们的想法，我和 Marco 会在这里回答
your questions.
你们的问题。
So I think we're out of time for today, but thanks for listening, and...
所以我想今天时间到了，但感谢收听，还有……
We'll see you there.
我们那里见。
Goodbye.
再见。
Bye.
拜。